Avinash A Tilekar (1) Featured

Senior Android Software Developer, Seeking roles in Android Application Development, Software Development, Requirement Gathering, Production Support, Solution Designing, Web Services, Core Java, Xml, Json, GIT, Experience 5.6+ years.



Total Experience: 7 Year(s) 0 Month(s) Current Designation: Senior Android Developer

Current Company: Peel-works Pvt. Ltd Notice Period: 2 Months

Current Location: Pune Highest Degree: MCA [Computers]

Pref. Location: Pune

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: senior android software developer, software development, requirement gathering, production support, solution designing,sql,android studio,git, tortoise svn, eclipse,freshdesk,mvc,mvvm,butt,butterknife,rxjava,firebase,Crashlytics

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 28-Jul-20 Last Modified: 28-Jul-20

Summary

5.9+ years of experience in Android Applications development.

FCM Notification implementation in Android Application.

PHP Rest API integration in Android Application.

Worked extensively on design and development of Android Applications

Experience in Android Studio & Eclipse.

Experience with SVN & Git.

Experience with RDBMS and writing SQL queries.

Experience with Web Services Communication in application with XML and JSON data.

API integration and custom control creation.

Experience integration and custom control creation.

Experience in creating runtime dynamic App GUI to support all screens size.

Extended work experience in production support and resolving the issues.

Good communicational, interpersonal, analytical and problem solving Skills.

Good team member with problem solving and trouble shooting skills

Conceptualized, designed, developed and deployed applications for android based mobile phones

Work Experience

Peel-works Pvt. Ltd as Senior Android Developer Apr 2018 to Till Date

Develops Application / Software solutions by studying information needs; conferring with users; studying systems flow, data usage, and work processes; investigating problem areas; following the software development lifecycle. Prepares and installs solutions by determining and designing system specifications, standards, and programming. Supports and develops software engineers by providing advice, coaching and educational opportunities.

ConstroBazaar Pvt LTD as Senior Android Software Developer Jan 2017 to Feb 2018

Designing module structure, layout, and project template with Singleton Design pattern.

Coding of application process flow with data validation, Creating common data validation functionality.

Ensure the best possible performance, quality, and responsiveness of the application. Creating API Call with help of Retrofit library.

Unit-testing with help of WhiteBox and BlackBox Testing and bug Fixing of App.

Work as Project Lead for requirements explanation to Team and help to all to get work done, code review.

ConstroBazaar Pvt LTD as Senior Android Developer

Jan 2017 to Apr 2018

Determines operational feasibility by evaluating analysis, problem definition, requirements, solution development, and proposed solutions.

Accomplishes engineering and organization mission by completing related results as needed.

Supports and develops software engineers by providing advice, coaching and educational opportunities.

Supports and develops software engineers by providing advice, coaching and educational opportunities.

Shivrai Technologies Pvt Ltd as Senior Android Software Developer

Mar 2014 to Dec 2016

Compserv Consultant Pvt. Ltd as HOD (Android and VB.net)

Jun 2012 to Feb 2014

Education

UG: BCA (Computers) from Shivaji University, Maharasthra in 2009

PG: MCA (Computers) from Shivaji University, Maharasthra in 2012

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience	
Android SDK		2020	7 Year(s) 1 Month(s)	
ANDROID		2020	7 Year(s) 1 Month(s)	
JAVA		2020	7 Year(s) 1 Month(s)	
Core Java, Android, Dot net, XML,JSON				
C,C++, SQL / PLSQL , Visual Basic 6.0				
ASP.net, HTML, JavaScript,VBScript.				
MS- Access, Oracle8i				
Eclipse, SVN.				
WINDOWS				
GIT				

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Proficient			
Hindi	Proficient			
Marathi	Expert			

Projects

Project Title: MDPP (ERP)

Client: Million Date Palm Plantation Project

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Oct 2015 - Jan 2016 Project Location: Muscat, Oman Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role: Sr. Programmer Team Size: 5 Skill Used: Android, JAVA, SQLite, XML, JSON, BarCode, SQL Server, ASP.Net

Role Description: Coding, Design

Project Details: MDPP application is basically created to maintaining the date palm tree Details of every farm. By using this we can see and enter all details of particular tree about his total water consumption, total fertilizer used for tree, what will be the estimated production of tree. Here we can also select tree via QR Code Scanner.

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No Employment Status: Full time